Let me now give you quick overview of icon fonts,
现在让我们大概地看一下图标字体
what are they, how are they used on websites, and
看一看它们是什么 应该怎么在网页中用它们
what advantages do they bring when you use them within your websites.
并看看应用它们有什么优势
Icon fonts are a set of icons and cliffs.
图标字体是一个图标集合
They can be used just like regular font on your website so
它们可以像普通的字体那样在你的网站中使用
just like you use your standard alphabets on your website,
就像标准的 abc 那样
you can use icon fonts in any location on your website.
图标字体可以在你网站中的任一位置应用
The advantages that icon fonts bring is that they can be easily styled using CSS.
应用图标字体的优势之一在于它们可以 简单地通过 CSS 来定制
Which means you can control the color, size and background and
这意味着你可以通过 CSS 来控制图标字体的
many other features of icon fonts using CSS.
颜色 大小 背景等各种特性
Icon fonts are a very light weight replacement for graphics on your webpages.
图标字体相对于普通图片而言是非常轻量级的
So if you have simple graphics, instead of using images,
所以如果你的网站中有一些比较简单的图片的话
you can use icon fonts as an easy replacement for them.
你可以尝试用图标字体去代替图片
Now when your web site includes icon fonts,
而当你的网站应用了图标字体时
they are downloaded without needing additional
它们将会自动下载到用户的电脑中
requests being sent to your web site in order to download the images.
而不会像普通图像那样向你的网页 发出一个额外的下载的请求
So that's one of the advantages why icon fonts have gained a lot of popularity
那也正是图标字体在网站中被广泛应用
in usage on websites.
的原因之一
Many different icon fonts are available that are used by website designers.
而且图标字体并不单调 事实上图标字体种类繁多
To help us understand how icon fonts are used in websites,
为了让你更直观地认知到什么是图标字体
let's quickly visit your course web page itself.
我们来看一下我们的课程主页
Now, on the left side in the side bar,
在左侧的这个侧栏中
you can see that we have a list of links there.
我们可以看到一个链接列表
In addition to the links, to the left side of the links,
在这个列表的每一项的左边
we also have small graphical icons included in the web page.
我们可以看到一个小图标
All these icons have been created using icon fonts.
这些小图标就是图标字体
Let's take a look at few example icon fonts that are used.
接下来让我们看看一些图标字体的样子
In particular, in this course, I'm gonna make you use of the Glyphicons.
而在这节课上 我们将会用 Glyphicons 这一图标字体集
Glyphicons are already included as part of the Bootstrap framework.
Glyphicons 是默认安装在了 Bootstrap 框架中的
In addition,
除了 Glyphicons 之外
I'm going to make use of Font Awesome, which is another popular icon font.
我们还将用到 Font Awesome 这一流行的图标字体集
As I mentioned, Glyphicons are already included in Bootstrap.
正如我刚刚说 Glyphicons 是 包含在 Bootstrap 里的
To make use of Glyphicons, on any location in your webpage, you use the span tag.
所以如果要用 Glyphicons 的话 只需要用一个 span 标签
To the span tag you will give a class as glyphicon and
然后对其设置 class="glyphicon xxx" 即可
then the specific class for the icon that you are using at the location.
其中 xxx 是特定的某个 Glyphicons 图标
So in this example you see me using the Glyphicon home as the second class there.
在这个栗子里面 xxx 就是 glyphicon-home
Glyphicon home corresponds to the home icon in the glyphicon set.
它对应着 Glyphicons 集里面的 home 图标
Glyphicons included in Bootstrap are about 250 in number.
Bootstrap 中的 Glyphicons 一共有 大约 250 个图标
Another popular icon font that I mentioned,
之前我提到的另一个有名的图标字体
that we will make use of in this course, is Font Awesome.
亦即 Font Awesome 也会在这节课中用到
Now Font Awesome includes a large set of icons.
Font Awesome 是一个很大的图标字体集
And provide you with a large variety of icons that you can use on your website.
它给了你海量的选择
Now once you take a look at Font Awesome you're gonna say, awesome man.
所以当你看向 Font Awesome 那浩如烟海的 图标集时 你一定会忍不住赞叹"好棒!"
Okay, okay, okay.
嘛 嘛 嘛
You can laugh as much as you want.
你可以尽情笑出来……
I am definitely not going to pretend to be a teenager.
我不会去装作我还年轻……
Okay coming back to icon fonts.
好的那么让我们回到正题……
They way you use icon fonts on your website, Is to use the i tag.
你在你的网站中应用图标字体的方法 是用 i 标签
To the i tag, you would give a class as fa and then fa hyphen
而在 i 标签中 你将会设置 class="fa xxx"
the specific icon that you're using at that location.
其中 xxx 对应着你想指定的那个图标字体
So in this example, you see me using fa fa phone, meaning the phone icon
在这个栗子里 xxx 就是 fa-phone 也即是一个 phone 图标
will be substituted in that particular location on your webpage.
这个小 phone 图标将会在 你网页的指定位置出现
How do you make use of Font Awesome in your web project?
那么怎么才能应用 Font Awesome 呢？
You need to download the Font Awesome distribution files, and then you
首先你要下载它
should include the CSS files that are part of Font Awesome, into your web project.
然后你需要在你的 web 项目中引用 Font Awesome 的 CSS 文件
And the fonts will automatically be used.
然后你就可以自如地应用这些图标字体了
Now one way that I use Font Awesome in my web projects
按照我的个人习惯的话
is after they download the Font Awesome distribution files,
在我下载完 Font Awesome 的所有配置文件后
then I will copy the CSS files from the CSS folder of the Font Awesome
我会将其中 CSS 文件夹里面的所有 CSS 文件
folder into the CSS folder of my web project.
都拷贝到我自己项目里的 CSS 文件夹中
And also I will copy the fonts from the Font Awesome folder into
我同时会将其中的 fonts 文件夹中的东西
the fonts folder of my web project.
拷贝到我的 fonts 文件夹中
That's how I have been using.
那是我的个人习惯
You can include these Font Awesome files in any other way that you choose to.
你当然也可以用其它的方法
Another CSS class that I am going to make use of in the exercise
我们在接下来的练习中还需要用到的
that follows this lecture is Bootstrap-social.
是一个叫 Bootstrap-social 的 CSS 类
Bootstrap-social is a CSS class that is available to
这个类会提供给你一些
style some buttons for social web sites.
社交网站的图标
Bootstrap-social makes use of Font Awesome's icon fonts that
Bootstrap-social 会在 Font Awesome 中表现
are representing the logos for the various social websites.
各路社交平台的 logo 的图标字体的基础上
Now, Bootstrap-social adds additional features to those Font Awesome icons.
加进一些额外的特性
So for example, it takes the Font Awesome icon and
比如说 它可以将一个 Font Awesome 的图标
then turns it into a button for the various social media sites.
转换成一个按钮
How do you make use of Bootstrap-social?
那么怎么才能应用 Bootstrap-social 呢？
You download Bootstrap-social.CSS file and then include it into your webpage.
只需要下载 bootstrap-social.css 文件 并在你的网页中引用之
Then wherever you need to include a button to a social
然后你就可以在你的网站中的任一个位置 通过一个 a 标签
website then you will include a A tag and give it a class as button.
并对其设置 class="btn btn-social-icon xxx" 来应用 Bootstrap-social 了
Button, of course, buttons which we will examine in the next module.
当然 Button 的细节是我们下一模块 才关心的东西
Then you specify buttons social icon,
而那个 xxx
and button for the specific social website.
就对应着特定的社交网站的 logo
So, in this example, you will see me referring to button Facebook, and
这个栗子里 我们用的是 btn-facebook
then In addition, you would be including
然后需要注意的是 在 a 标签中还需要
the Font Awesome icon for that particular social media site.
用一个 i 标签来引用 Font Awesome 图标
So that's why you see me using there the i class, fa, and the fa-facebook
当然这个 Font Awesome 图标 也需要是 Facebook 的图标
to use the Facebook icon that is included as part of the Font Awesome set.
所以 class 里面我们用的是 fa-facebook
Now we will move on to our next hands on exercise.
接下来我们就要进行我们下一个练习了
We will, in this exercise, go back to the website what we have been designing so
在这个练习中 我们将会在 我们已经设计了挺久的网页上
far and then include the nav bar into our web page.
加入导航栏
In addition, we'll make use of both Glyphicons and
同时 我们还将在我们网页上的一些地方
then Font Awesome icons in various locations on our web page.
实现一些 Glyphicons 和 Font Awesome 的图标
We'll also use Bootstrap-social to include some social
最后 我们还会应用 Bootstrap-social 来在我们的页脚处引入一些
website buttons in the footer of our webpage.
长得和某些社交网站 logo 一样的按钮 【翻译 - Carefree0910】